<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!-- 
// 
// This is the place for your statements. The maximum 
// number of statements is theoretically unlimited, but
// less then 50 statements are advisable.
// If your are using German Umlauts and other special 
// characters, make sure, that you save this XML-file 
// as an UTF-8-document. White-space inbetween the 
// nodes are ignored. Any white-space within the text-
// nodes, including leading or trailing whitespace and 
// line breaks, is preserved.
//
// EXAMPLE
// Let's define some statements concerning FlashQ:
// Statement 1: FlashQ is very usefull.
// Statement 2: I prefer offline surveys.
// Statement 3: FlashQ is too complicated to configure.
//
// Each statement requires a seperate statement-node 
// consisting out of an opening and a closing tag. The 
// statement itself goes between this two tags. 
// The unique statement id is saved as an 
// attribute called 'id'. We have three exmaple 
// statements and we need therefore three statement-
// nodes and one parent-node. 
//
// <statements version="1.0" htmlparse="false">
//   <statement id="1">FlashQ is very usefull.</statement>
//   <statement id="2">I prefer offline surveys.</statement>
//   <statement id="3">FlashQ is too complicated to configure</statement>
// </statements>
// 
// ===================================================
// 
-->

<statements version="1.0" htmlParse="false">
  <statement id="1">The government cannot be trusted to prioritize First Nations issues.</statement>
  <statement id="2">The Chiefs of the reserves cannot be trusted to handle the government's funding properly.</statement>
  <statement id="3">Safe clean drinkable water is a human right.</statement>
  <statement id="4">It is unconstitutional that First Nations people need to move off reserves to urban areas to access clean water.</statement>
  <statement id="5">Ignoring First Nations water quality issues devalues them as human beings.</statement>
  <statement id="6">As a developed country conditions of First Nations water quality are shameful.</statement>
  <statement id="7">First Nations people shouldn’t be given preferential treatment over other communities living with water quality issues.</statement>
  <statement id="8">A densely populated city would never have a 20 year boil advisory.</statement>
  <statement id="9">The First Nations people have sufficient access to potable water.</statement>
  <statement id="10">First Nations people don’t have the training/expertise to maintain the water treatment plants.</statement>
  <statement id="11">Simply chlorinating the water is not a sustainable solution.</statement>
  <statement id="12">We shouldn’t stand idly and watch this injustice remain unchallenged.</statement>
  <statement id="13">I personally do not see an issue with drinking bottled water.</statement>
  <statement id="14">Having to walk for long periods of time for drinkable water is emotionally and physically draining.</statement>
  <statement id="15">There are greater benefits for First Nations people by managing their own water quality affairs.</statement>
  <statement id="16">Governments of all levels need to provide support to all the reservations to make amends for past injustices.</statement>
  <statement id="17">The mismanagement of resources by the First Nations communities is the reason why their water quality is poor.</statement>
  <statement id="18">It's not up to us to dictate to the Government of Canada how to solve water quality issues for First Nations people.</statement>
  <statement id="19">The Canadian government should be cooperative when working with First Nations people.</statement>
  <statement id="20">First Nations people are counting on taxpayer money to fix the issue for them.</statement>
  <statement id="21">The governemnt should prioritize our funds towards the third world water conditions found on First Nations reserves.</statement>
  <statement id="22">The money used to ship in bottled water should be used to create the needed infrastructure.</statement>
</statements>
